Nannapaneni Saikiran

Delhi, India | J+91 7569767364 | ⊕ Portfolio | ■ saikiran8844n@gmail.com | 匝 LinkedIn | ♠ Github

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Versatile developer presently working as Junior Software Developer, distinguished for collaborative skills and a track record of independently delivering impactful results. Ample experience in full-stack development, delivering well-documented, tested, and operable code. Efficient in collaborating and communicating new ideas and opinions.

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Postman API Fundamentals Student Expert | Postman

Peer Mentor | Department of English - GEC

Trailhead Expenditure badge holder | *Salesforce*

Python Certification | Coursera

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, java, SQL (MySQL), JavaScript, HTML, XML, JSON, CSS,

Frameworks: SpringBoot, Jstl, React Js, Bootstrap

DevOps and API Tools: Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Azure DevOps, GCP, Jenkins, Swagger, Postman

Cloud and Security Tools: AWS, Keycloak, SQL Server

Others: Agile Methodologies (Scrum), Design Patterns, Debugging, Root Cause Analysis

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer 1 | *Thales*

April 2023 -Present

- Spearheaded the successful execution of a full-stack development project, enhancing website performance by 40% and increasing user engagement by 25% through well-documented and tested code implementation.
- Well-versed in diverse technologies to create robust and scalable solutions. Skilled in developing Swagger API, SAP
 connectors, and portals, seamlessly integrating disparate systems for optimized performance.
- Strong understanding of building and deploying applications using Bamboo and GCP Cloud Build, ensuring efficient and streamlined processes. Proficient in Kubernetes and Ansible for deploying applications, and adept at utilizing Docker for containerization to facilitate smooth deployment workflows
- Proficient in Agile methodologies, with a deep understanding of Jira, Scrum/Kanban, Confluence, Bitbucket, and the Agile development life-cycle, driving efficient project management and collaboration.

Graduate Trainee | *Kodnest*

December 2022 - April 2023

- Worked on Java and Python-based full-stack development, acquiring foundational knowledge in manual testing methodologies. Equipped with industry-standard skills in these languages, capable of developing robust and versatile software solutions
- Completed a rigorous and structured training program within the company, gaining comprehensive insights into various facets of business operations, thereby enhancing industrial adaptability and proficiency.
- Gained valuable insights into industry-level technologies and software development practices, positioning me as a versatile software engineer capable of contributing to various projects.

EDUCATION

GEC Gudlavalleru Sri Chaitanya jr College Nagarjuna High School

Bachelor's in Electronics And Communication Engineering | GPA: 8.61 Intermediate | Percentage: 95

SSC | GPA:9.3

June 2018 – April 2022 June 2016 – May 2018 June 2015 – May 2016

PROJECTS

Analysis-of-Anime-Recommendations-Dataset | Python, Jupiter Notebook, MySQL

- Orchestrated keen knowledge in SQL and Python in the analysis of anime-based datasets.
- Achieved 75% faster analysis of data by cleaning the data and reported analysis on pictorial form for better understanding
 of analysis.

Portfolio Website | HTML, CSS, is

- A Self-esteemed portfolio describing end-to-end details of my industrial experience.
- A kick-start static web application demonstrating my hands-on experience with the web tech stack.

Food Recipe API | Java.

- Robust API Describing the food recipe based on the driven calls with basic auth.
- To leverage and enhance proficiency in Rest API created a Swagger that describes recipes based on the request.